2940 BORJA ST. BINAN, LAGUNA

Viber: +63-969-523-7638

Email: rdsaavedra15@gmail.com Website: https://www.jetdev.info/



RAMIL D. SAAVEDRA

OBJECTIVE

A self-motivated and enthusiastic individual seeking an opportunity to be part of your organization as a Web Developer. With my eagerness to learn new technologies and acquired skills from 3 years of web application development using vanilla technologies and frameworks, I will be able to contribute to your team's vision.

PROJECTS

Web Blocker (Chrome Extension) - webblockerextension.com

Technologies used: ReactJS / Typescript - (Webpack, NextJS, Typescript, Chrome Manifest V3)

- Restrict users from accessing websites using Chrome Manifest V3
- Configure Webpack to use ReactJS and Typescript for faster development
- Design and deploy the official website using NextJS, Figma, and Vercel
- Submit and publish code based on google chrome standards.

jetdev.info (personal portfolio) - jetdev.info

Technologies used: ReactJS / Typescript - (NextJS, Firebase)

- Design and code a mobile-friendly UI
- Utilize different rendering options offered by NextJS
- Integrate 3rd party API (Spotify)
- Using firebase as the backend/database

End to End Content Management System (e2e)

Technologies used: React / Nodejs

- Full system flow of flowerstore.ph for organizing and dispatching of orders.
- Created a reusable UI for the system
- Collaborated with back-end developers

Flowerstore.ph - <u>flowerstore.ph</u>

Technologies used: Laravel - (PHP, JS, CSS, HTML)

- Order restriction based on date and time
- Dynamic computation of products prices based on dates
- Mobile Responsive Design

Minimart.ph

Technologies used: Laravel - (PHP, JS, CSS, HTML)

- Redesign flowerstore.ph into minimart.ph
- Improved mobile design

Fans.ph

Technologies used: Laravel - (PHP, JS, CSS, HTML)

- Convert design / wireframes into HTML/CSS code
- Mobile responsive design

EXPERIENCE

Flowerstore Group

Web Developer (April 2019 - March 2021)

- Team up with Senior and other developers to come up with the best solutions to complex problems
- Collaborate with marketing heads to implement marketing strategies into website functionality
- Work with the designers and heads to translate designs into HTML/CSS code

Pictureworks Group Pty. Ltd.

Full-stack Web Developer (March 2021 - May 2021)

- Adding new features based on the client's request
- Porting of legacy PHP app to new Laravel app
- Work on front-end for Zensmart app (reactJS)
- Collaborate with other developers on tweaking current features to suit client's needs

Freelance Developer

```
(March 2021 - Present)
```

I worked as a freelance web developer to improve my chosen skill (stack) and to meet and grow with another fantastic developer.

SKILLS

```
Typescript, NextJS, CSS, Firebase, ReactJS, GitHub, Figma, PHP, Laravel, MySQL, BitBucket, Jira
```

EDUCATION

```
Saint Michael's College of Laguna — Bachelor's Degree
```

CFRTIFICATE

```
React Front to Back 2022 - <a href="link">link</a>
Typescript: The Complete Developer's Guide) - <a href="link">link</a>
React Front to Back 2020 - <a href="link">link</a>
Complete React Developer in 2021 (w/ Redux, Hooks, GraphQL) - <a href="link">link</a>
```